The World of Six Gates.
They are:
Fire,
Wind,
Water,
Earth,
Light,
Darkness.
These are what this mysterious world is made up of.
A wondrous world inhabited with various monsters.
This is a story of the adventures of a boy and a girl in this world of monsters,
a story of love and friendship.
Just kidding!
I'm counting on you, partner. Scorching Breath!
Songstress of the Flower Garden, protect everyone using Resistance!
Let me explain.
Here, everyone is playing Monster Collection.
A super popular card game set in The World of Six Gates.
Man, wouldn't it be really cool if The World of Six Gates really existed?
I wanna see the monsters like the ones in Monster Collection!
And this boy is a huge fan of Mon Colle, a fifth-grader Mondo Ooya.
Don't be stupid, Mon!
Has Papa poisoned your mind again?
Explaining further: this beautiful girl is our heroine, Rokuna Hiiragi!
R-Rokuna! No, it's not like that...
I was just hoping the professor's research was going smoothly.
I've had enough of that!
The only thing Papa ever does is his Six Gates research!
Mama went back to her parents' house because of that...
Uh, Rokuna?
Ah, but that's okay, Mon.
There's a ghost in front of that locker.
Ehhhh?
I have to explain some more.
This girl, Rokuna Hiiragi, is a medium.
She can see ghosts where normal people can't see them!
Y-You're the same as ever, Rokuna...
Anyways, because of Papa's research, I...
Rokuna, you have me, don't you?
Right, Rokuna?
Ah, Mon!
Rokuna...
Good morning, everyone! I'm your homeroom teacher, Namiko Gokumare.
Let's start studying— huh?
Rokuna, I love you.
Mon, I love you too.
Hey!
Elementary schoolers shouldn't be having a love scene in the afternoon!
Namiko hasn't had a boyfriend in her 29 years!
I'll become an old maid soon... Wait a minute!
Rokuna...
Mon...
I'm saying...
It's my home! Papa!
We've got a problem!
I want love...
Papa! Papa!
Professor! Are you alright?
I did it! At last, I did it!
Now, this old man is Rokuna's father, Ichiroubei Hiiragi.
He's apparently famous for his research of The World of Six Gates.
Papa, are you alright?
Professor?
Oh, my beloved daughter Rokuna!
And of course, Dia Mondo.
It's Ooya!
You two, listen here. I did it. At last, I did it!
Eh? But you're an adult, Papa!
Did you take a dump? Or did you pee? Or maybe-
Wroooong!
I finally discovered The World of Six Gates!
Hey, what's with the skeptical looks?
I have discovered the door between the real world and The World of Six Gates,
known as the Dream Hole.
Furthermore, using this Flying Dragon, it's possible to go to The World of Six Gates!
Flying Dragon!
It's a dragon-shaped parallel world transport!
So amazing!
I can ride it to go to The World of Six Gates!
I can't wait to see the monsters!
I won! I beat that Collection dumbass!
Collection dumbass?
This is an old castle deep in a German forest.
Elohim essam...
I am seeking...
You're so cool, Count!
That was wonderful, Count!
Right on!
Ah, really? It was?
And this man is...
professor Ichiroubei Hiiragi's rival, Count Collection.
He's also an outstanding scientist.
Who, me? Aww, thanks!
However, he is gay!
Behave according to your position!
I hate violence...
Ara-ara~
Again!
Anyways, I did it at last!
I have discovered Dream Hole to The World of Six Gates.
With it, I can go see Six Gates!
I wanna see it, too!
Are you okay in the head?
For Count Ludwig Presto Von Meinstein Collection, there's no such thing as "impossible"!
Watch this. Observe.
Look! This is Monster Hunter!
Moreover, we may have found a Mon-Mon Item!
Mon-Mon Item?
What's that?
Fire, Wind, Water, Earth, Light, Darkness —
the magical items of these six elements.
After so many years of research!..
When you assemble all six Mon-Mon Items, you can connect The World of Six Gates and this world.
Therefore,
You can bring monsters from that world here!
That's when I'm going to command the army of monsters and conquer the world!
By connecting our world and The World of Six Gates
and having cultural exchange all over the world, humanity will definitely advance even further!
At that point I'm going to be renowned for great contributions to human progress!
Let's go!
To The World of Six Gates!
Roger!
Flying Dragon, launch!
When I obtain all Mon-Mon Items, I'll become the ruler of the entire world!
Flying Lion, launch!
Let's go!
Leave it to us!
To the sky!
Now, let's watch the movie "Welcome to Collection's Room of Roses"!
Sure!
By the way, do you know my name?
Of course we do!
Please, say it.
One, two!
Count Ludwig Presto Von Meinstein Collection!
Ah, you did it so well!
Now, let's do it together again:
One, two!
Count Ludwig Presto Von Meinstein Collection.
Meh, so expressionless.
Count Ludwig Presto Von Meinstein Collection!
Now, with your mother and your father too!
One, two!
Count Ludwig Presto Von Meinstein Collection!
Well done!
We're soon arriving at The World of Six Gates!
I'm going to see them.
Soon, all the monsters that I've seen in the game before...
EHHHHH?
Amazing! Forest Giant and Behemoth are fighting!
Is that?..
Princess of the elves, Songstress of the Flower Garden!
It's Pegasus!
Amazing, amazing, amazing!
Our world and The World of Six Gates are really connected now!
You're amazing, professor! You really did it!
It hurts! Mondo, it hurts!
Bo-i-ng!
Finally here! This is The World of Six Gates!
Ah, this feeling...
Us humans have just taken a huge step into the future!
Uh, Mon, this doesn't matter, but...
Isn't it kinda hot?
Aaaah! There's fire! Fire!
Haha, don't panic.
This is a forest of burning trees.
Forest of burning trees?
Now, let's look for Mon-Mon Items!
What's this thing?
I'm so happy you asked!
This is monster detector!
Or, as I call it, Cluck Detector!
Quack Detector?
Wrooong! Cluck Detector!
When there's a monster above it, it clucks!
When there's a monster below it, it clucks!
If it's reacting like crazy, then the monster has a Mon-Mon Item!
Let's see now...
Huh?
Cute!
That's Lovestar!
A monster of Light which is said to bring small happiness.
Huh? Such small monsters exist, too?
However, Cluck Detector doesn't seem to be reacting much,
so it's not a very high-level monster.
Uh, wait!
Let's go, Rokuna!
Hey, wait, you two!
I know this place is fascinating, but these guys are hopeless...
Huh? Already detecting a monster?
Here it comes!
The opposite of north is south!
Well— yuck, that's you!
Ahahahahaha!
Where did Lovestar go?
Huh?
Eh?
Excuse me, what are you doing?
You don't know?
Here we're gathering burning tree branches from the forest for the living.
Branches?
This fire is magical.
We sell it to other lands.
So it's this land's local specialty, huh?
In this forest lives the legendary Fire Dragon.
Legendary...
Fire Dragon?
Children!
Oh?
You two have mysterious power, don't you?
Eh?
And you are?..
This village's fortune-telling witch.
And you two are...
E-Excuse me?
You aren't a Summoner.
Yes!
You can emotionally connect to monsters' hearts.
Eh? Monsters?
Your medium ability is strong.
If you work with this boy,
You'll be able to wield tremendous power.
If you're ever in peril, try saying "Adara-kadara-boo".
"Adara-kadara-boo"?
These are magic words from very ancient times.
Adara-kadara-boo!
Eaaaargghh!
Ah, Papa!
Professor!
Stop that, Collection!
Is this the way to treat senior apprentice?
Silence! You're in the way of our plan!
Hmmm... You can become prey for the monsters here.
Collection! What do you think you're doing?!
Ahahahahahaha!
I'm going to take control of the monsters, obtain all six Mon-Mon Items,
and, in the end, become the ruler of both The World of Six Gates and the real world!
I won't allow that!
Huh?
Villain! Do you plan to use my beloved monsters for evil deeds?
Now I'm mad!
Who's there?
Protecting the peace in The World of Six Gates...
and the future of the monsters...
We're warriors of justice,
Mon Colle Knights!
You're finally here...
Scissors Jab!
Scissors wha—
How interesting...
Wait-wait-wait! What?
Go forth! Knight Tape!
Eeeeeeeek!
Heave-ho!
Aaaah! I'm spinning! Spinning! Spi-spi-spinning!
Eeeeh? Mon Colle Knights, my ass!
Are you defying the ruler of this world, Count Collection?
You mean the gaylord of this world?
Silence! Shut up!
It means it's the time to show how terrifying I am, isn't it?
Roger!
Right!
This is my Tanuki Detector!
Tan-tan-tanuki is a detector!
Even without wind its ball swing back and forth!
Good, isn't it?
Come to me, Lava Chimera!
Woah! It's the real Lava Chimera!
This isn't something to be happy about!
Now, make Chimera the first one to join my monster collection!
On that!
Hahaha! We'll combine it with Flying Lion!
See! The triumph of science!
Now, Lava Chimera, annihilate these guys!
Run!
Rokuna!
Mon!
You aren't escaping!
This is the price you pay for being in the way!
Butcher them, Lava Chimera!
I wonder if it's okay to do bad things like this...
Eeeeeeeeeeeeh!
Aaaaaaaaaaah!
Huh? That is...
Byan bya-ya-ya ya nyan! Nya bya nyan nyan byan byan!
It's bad! We must save her!
Impossible! In such situation...
But, are you really going to leave her?
Rokuna, Mondo!
Woah!
Ouch...
Don't push, Mondo! It's gonna come out!
Lovestar! You aren't hurt, are you?
Damn! What's with love-something?
It's because of you that we went here to the very bottom.
Huh?
This is!..
Fire Dragon...
This is...
I hear it.
Fire Dragon's... hearbeat.
Ohohoho! You ended up in such a place?
I'll get you soon.
Eh?
Collection, you bastard!
Rokuna, remember what the fortune teller told us?
About us having great power together!
Yes, Mon!
Uh?
Please, Fire Dragon!
Lend us your power!
Adara-kadara-boo!
Now, trample these fools at once!
Eh? What's this?
Huh? Say again?
My, my...
Ooooh!
Ah! That is...
Our... soul link to the monsters!
Let me explain!
After uttering that spell, Mondo and Rokuna can possess the monster!
Is that even fair?
Ah, destroy them!
Go! Scorching Breath!
What the heck, Count?
At this point, I have to use the Combat Spell!
Lava Chimera: Reverse Lightning!
That is...
Let me explain.
Lava Chimera can use Combat Spells, a special type of magic.
If you use the Reverse Lightning Combat Spell with your Chimera,
the electricity will strike the Fire Dragon and stop it from moving!
Fight on, Fire Dragon!
Fire Dragon!
Ohohoho! What, did you think you won?
At this pace, I'll be able to conquer both the real world and The World of Six Gates!
Count, please reconsider!
Sounds interesting!..
Ohohohohohoho!
I won't allow that!
Using my beloved monsters...
and troubling both real world and The World of Six Gates...
I won't lose to such a guy!
Uh-huh...
Eeeh? That's the!..
Let me explain!
Fire Dragon responded to Mondo and Rokuna's courage and kindness!
Furthermore, right now, thanks to this possession, it transformed into Final Fire Dragon!
Final Fire Dragon...
Huh? What's that?
Next, Lava Chimera, use Fire Javelin!
Blergh.
Go, Final Fire Dragon!
Explosive Breath!
What? What's going on?
Oaaaahhh!
Please watch the TV show too!
Warriors of justice,
Mon Colle Knights!
You two have done well!
Your kindness guided you to the victory!
Papa, so shameless...
Thanks...
Final Fire Dragon.
But, seriously, wasn't this super exciting?
Possessing a monster!
Mhm.
That's right! Look here.
So pretty!
Professor, could that be?..
Correct! That's the Mon-Mon Item of Fire, The Ruby Ring!
Seems that Lava Chimera dropped it.
So this is a Mon-Mon Item...
Right, five more left! And then my dream will come true!
Somehow doesn't sound that easy.
But that's alright.
Because we worked so hard,
we were able to become friends with such a cute Lovestar!
Now, it's time to move!
Yup! Lovestar, take care!
Bye!
No, you can't go with us.
Come on, return to the forest!
I'm asking you, please, go back.
Goodbye.
I said no! Goodbye!
It can't be that she...
She thinks "Jahnay" is her name, doesn't she?
It seems that the Lovestar took a liking to you.
How about taking her with you?
Eh? But...
What? You can communicate with monsters, can't you?
Don't let it concern you.
Then...
I'm sure she'll be happier this way, too.
Ahhh, thanks a lot! Yay!
From now on, take care of us, Lovestar!
I mean, Jahnay!
It's said that Lovestar can bring small happiness.
I suppose if we take her back to the real world,
she'll become the first envoy of peace between the two worlds!
Yep!
By the way, I still haven't heard your guys' names.
We are Knights!
Uh?
Protecting the peace in The World of Six Gates...
and the future of the monsters...
We're warriors of justice, Mon Colle Knights!
Let me explain!
Mondo and Rokuna's heart-thrilling adventure has just begun!
Aaaaah! The hypnosis has worn off!
Why is it chasing me?!
Huh? Huh?
Please go away! Away! Away!
Someone heeeeeelp!
Quit chasing us!
Why is it still after us?! Help!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!